
<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<metadata>

These example Royalty Agreement are actual legal documents drafted by top law firms for their clients. Use them as Royalty Agreement samples, Royalty Agreement templates, competitive intelligence, drafting documents or to get information about transactions within a particular industry or sector. We have millions of legal documents and clauses that you can search for free.
A consensus tree is a phylogenetic tree that summarizes a given collection of
phylogenetic trees having the same leaf labels but different branching structures.
Consensus trees are used to resolve structural differences between two or
more existing phylogenetic trees arising from conflicts in the raw data, to find
strongly supported groupings, and to summarize large sets of candidate trees obtained
by bootstrapping when trying to infer a new phylogenetic tree accurately
[2, 10, 12, 27].
Since the first type of consensus tree was proposed by Adams III [1] in 1972,
many others have been defined and analyzed. See, e.g., [5], Chapter 30 in [12],
or Chapter 8.4 in [27] for some surveys. Which particular type of consensus
tree to use in practice depends on the context. For example, the strict consensus
tree [25] is very intuitive and easy to compute [9] and may be sufficient when there
is not so much disagreement in the data, the majority rule consensus tree [21]
is “the optimal tree to report if we view the cost of reporting an estimate of
the phylogeny to be a linear function of the number of incorrect clades in the
estimate and the number of true clades that are missing from the estimate and we
 Funded by The Hakubi Project and KAKENHI grant number 23700011.
A. Darling and J. Stoye (Eds.): WABI 2013, LNBI 8126, pp. 141–155, 2013.
c
Springer-Verlag Berlin Heidelberg 2013
142 J. Jansson, C. Shen, and W.-K. Sung
T : 1
a b
c
d
e
T : 2
a b c d
e
T : 3
a b
c e
d
T : 4
c d
b
a
e
Majority rule:
a b
c d e
Majority rule (+):
a b
c d
e
Frequency diff.:
a b c d
e
Fig. 1. Let S = {T1, T2, T3, T4} as shown above with L = Λ(T1) = Λ(T2) = Λ(T3) =
Λ(T4) = {a, b, c, d, e}. The only non-trivial majority cluster of S is {a, b}, the nontrivial
majority (+) clusters of S are {a, b} and {a, b, c, d}, and the non-trivial frequency
difference clusters of S are {a, b}, {a, b, c, d}, and {c, d}. The majority rule, majority
rule (+), and frequency difference consensus trees of S are displayed.
view the reporting of an incorrect grouping as a more serious error than missing
a clade” [16], and the R* consensus tree [5] provides a statistically consistent
estimator of the species tree topology when combining gene trees [10]. Therefore,
scientists need efficient algorithms for constructing a broad range of different
consensus trees.
In a recent series of papers [8, 17–19], we have developed fast algorithms for
computing the majority rule consensus tree [21], the loose consensus tree [4]
(also known in the literature as the combinable component consensus tree or the
semi-strict consensus tree), a greedy consensus tree [5, 13], the R* consensus
tree [5], and consensus trees for so-called multi-labeled phylogenetic trees (MULtrees)
[20]. In this paper, we study two relatively new types of consensus trees
called the majority rule (+) consensus tree [7, 11] and the frequency difference
consensus tree [14], and give algorithms for constructing them efficiently.
1.1 Definitions and Notation
We shall use the following basic definitions. A phylogenetic tree is a rooted,
unordered, leaf-labeled tree in which every internal node has at least two children
and all leaves have different labels. (Below, phylogenetic trees are referred to as
“trees” for short). For any tree T , the set of all nodes in T is denoted by V (T )
and the set of all leaf labels in T by Λ(T ). Any nonempty subset C of Λ(T) is
called a cluster of Λ(T ); if |C| = 1 or C = Λ(T) then C is trivial, and otherwise
</metadata>